<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Luke Segars</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Luke Segars</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Glimpse: early-Dec update</title>
      <link>/posts/glimpse-early-dec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/glimpse-early-dec/</guid>
      <description>Lots of exciting progress since the mid-Nov update &amp;ndash; here are some shots of the latest:
                  There&#39;s a lot of new stuff here, and some things exist but aren&#39;t visible yet. Notable additions:
 Completely changed how continents are being generated. My original plan was to double down on my plate tectonics-based approach, but it wasn&#39;t producing satisfying results, so I backtracked and did a bunch of reading on how to make terrain out of random noise (simplex noise, specifically).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glimpse: mid-Nov update</title>
      <link>/posts/glimpse-mid-nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/glimpse-mid-nov/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;ve made progress! Glimpse is starting to come to life.
New worlds are far more interesting than they were last week. White dots are cities, heatmap is elevation.
The new maps have a lot of the improvements I laid out in my last article. There&#39;s still a lot of work to do artistically on making these ready to print, but feature-wise we&#39;re getting pretty close to v1. Primary improvements are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundations of world generation</title>
      <link>/posts/foundations-of-world-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/foundations-of-world-generation/</guid>
      <description>Over the last two weeks I&#39;ve refined the goals of my own world generator and gone back to the drawing board on how to be successful. This has involved reading up on a ton of prior work, the best of which is provided below.
Refined goal My goal is to generate worlds that look good when printed; this project will be successful once I can generate enough high-quality maps to make a coffee table book that I don&#39;t have to hide in a drawer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My procedural world generator</title>
      <link>/posts/my-procedural-world-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-procedural-world-generator/</guid>
      <description>I grew up interested in fantasy worlds and have been hooked on the idea of building them since I was in middle school. Programmatically generating these worlds is one of my go-to projects when I feel like coding, and I&#39;ve been merging a few of these efforts into a single codebase that I can add onto every now and then to gradually get better results. It&#39;s way too fun, even if the world quality still isn&#39;t very good yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making predictable decisions</title>
      <link>/posts/making-predictable-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/making-predictable-decisions/</guid>
      <description>How many people you work with could predict your answers to things that are &amp;ldquo;your job&amp;rdquo; to weigh in on? If someone on your team asked you whether X or Y was more important, who would know your answer before you said it?
Knowing what someone will say depends on understanding why they&#39;ll say it, and at work teams can move a lot faster and make stickier decisions if they&#39;re clear on the rationale and trade-offs of doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cashcow: flexible financial simulations</title>
      <link>/posts/cashcow-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cashcow-intro/</guid>
      <description>Cashcow is a tool for simulating longer-term financial projections with a focus on answering questions that start with &amp;ldquo;what if.&amp;rdquo; I&#39;m currently using this for my own personal finances, but there are some other use cases I&#39;m interested to explore documented below.
Example questions I want to be able to answer:
 What if I start investing $250 / month into my mutual fund after my next raise instead of $100?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dropd: easy local file sharing</title>
      <link>/posts/dropd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dropd/</guid>
      <description>Copying files between home computers is surprisingly complicated. I often need to move something from one computer to another (audio or video recordings, photos, disk images, etc) and regularly struggle.
 Dropbox et al work well and are my preferred option, but can be slow (esp. Dropbox) and a I almost never remember to delete things when I’m done. Flash drives are always there except when I need them. FTP servers and network drives are a great idea but hard to interface with, especially if I’m trying to do a one-time copy to or from a friend or visitors computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrapping up our podcast</title>
      <link>/posts/in-over-our-heads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/in-over-our-heads/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;ve been working on In Over Our Heads for about eleven months now, and we&#39;ve decided to quit recording new episodes. We&#39;ve taken this so much further than I thought we would&#39;ve in some ways, and I&#39;ve documented few victories and insights as we close this project out. A full episode list is available at the bottom of this post.
Victories  We originally set out to create five episodes of this show and we closed out with nineteen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elite Dangerous Paths</title>
      <link>/posts/elite-dangerous-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/elite-dangerous-paths/</guid>
      <description>Elite Dangerous is a popular spacefaring game that puts you in the middle of an absolutely massive universe (~400 billion explorable galaxies) with a variety of objectives to accomplish. Navigation is therefore pretty important to the game, and different ships and ship upgrades allow you to travel further than others, so different pilots will operate under different constraints based on the ship they&#39;re flying.
The navigation tools in the game are good enough if you&#39;re trying to plan simple routes between points, but it&#39;s tough to do anything more complex using the in-game tools, including:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>